Nicholas Hoyt

Front-End Developer

Phone:	Address:	
Email:	LinkedIn:	https://www.linkedin.com/in/nhoy

Software development professional with over 25 years of experience specializing in user interface development for web applications and browser extensions. Experience with modern JavaScript, HTML, CSS, web accessibility, DOM events, WebExtensions API, web components and custom element authoring.

Experience

2005-09 - present

Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Designed and developed browser extensions for Firefox and Chrome, including Alnspector, a web accessibility evaluation tool for Firefox, and SkipTo Landmarks & Headings, an assistive technology for keyboard-only users for both Chrome and Firefox.

Designed and developed five CKEditor plugins for the A11yFirst Project: Heading/Paragraph, Image, Link, Character Style and Help. These plugins proactively guide content authors as they edit, enabling them to meet the accessibility requirements of WCAG 2.0.

Designed and developed the Accessibility Bookmarklets, which are web accessibility visualization tools compatible with all major browsers and available at accessibility-bookmarklets.org.

Designed and developed the Functional Accessibility Evaluator, a Django/Python web application that uses web crawling to evaluate the accessibility of websites based on requirements in WCAG, ARIA and HTML 5.

1999-08 - 2005-09

Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

Web UI, Wheaton, IL

As an independent contractor, provided software design and development services with an emphasis on interaction design and front-end development for various corporate clients, including ABN AMRO, Accenture, Allstate Insurance, DeVry University, Fidelity Investments, HOLT Value Associates and the Illinois Institute of Technology.

1997-08 - 1999-08

Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

Fidelity Investments, Marlborough, MA

Served as lead interaction designer in the redesign of NetBenefits, a web application providing retirement savings account access to over one million customers. Improved the user experience through contextual inquiry, task flow analysis and usability testing.

Designed and developed retirement investing tools for 401k.com, Fidelity's website for institutional investors. Tools included the Contribution Calculator, Withdrawal Calculator and Take Home Pay Calculator.

1991-07 - 1997-08

Front-End Developer, Senior Software Engineer

BGS Systems, Waltham, MA

Developed feature enhancements for the BEST/1 capacity planning and performance analysis

Nicholas Hoyt

products, using X Window / Motif on the Unix and VMS platforms. Completed the training course provided by Digital Equipment Corp. on X Window/Motif user interface development.

Education

1988-09 - 1991-06	B.A. in Computer Science, University of Massachusetts Boston Graduated with Honors, Summa Cum Laude
1987-09 - 1988-01	Introduction to Programming, Harvard Extension School Grade: A; for Undergraduate Credit
1981-09 - 1984-06	Jazz Composition & Arranging Major, Berklee College of Music Completed all course work for my major with GPA of 3.85/4.0
1967-09 - 1970-08	Liberal Arts and Sciences, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign Primarily focused on philosophy and psychology

Skills

Front-End Development

JavaScript (ES6 and later), HTML, CSS, DOM scripting and event handling, responsive design, web components and custom element authoring, Lit, React, WebExtensions API

User Interface Design

Experience with creating wireframes and interactive prototypes, essential use cases, usability testing and accessibility evaluation

Web Accessibility

WCAG requirements, ARIA Authoring Practices, ARIA in HTML

Web Development

Git, Node.js, npm, Babel, webpack, Rollup, Gulp, XML/XSLT, Django, Python